<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - Silvia Sellán</title>
        <link>https://www.silviasellan.com/posts.html</link>
        <description>All Posts | Silvia Sellán</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>sgsellan@cs.toronto.edu (Silvia Sellán)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>sgsellan@cs.toronto.edu (Silvia Sellán)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.silviasellan.com/posts.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Quick 2D prototyping with Gpytoolbox I: Generating 2D polylines </title>
    <link>https://www.silviasellan.com/gpytoolbox-2d-prototyping.html</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://www.silviasellan.com/gpytoolbox-2d-prototyping.html</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Gpytoolbox version 0.1.0 has just been released!! You can install it directly through pip:
1  pip install gpytoolbox   Gpytoolbox shines when it comes to letting you test out your research ideas on simple 2D geometry before you commit to more complex three-dimensional examples and elaborately optimized implementations. Often, our final algorithm will use triangle meshes to represent surfaces in 3D. This means that, when prototyping in 2D, we will work with its equivalent: curves built by connecting flat segments (edges), which are usually called polylines.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Quick 2D prototyping with Gpytoolbox II: Sampling 2D polylines</title>
    <link>https://www.silviasellan.com/gpytoolbox-2d-prototyping-2.html</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://www.silviasellan.com/gpytoolbox-2d-prototyping-2.html</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Gpytoolbox version 0.1.0 has just been released!! You can install it directly through pip:
1  pip install gpytoolbox   This is the second in a series of blogposts highlighting features of our newly released library. You can find rest of the blog entries here. Today, we are looking at how to compute distances to 2D polylines.
In the last tutorial, we saw how to load simple two-dimensional polylines into Python using gpytoolbox to quickly test our research code on.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Compressing a massive TeX folder for submitting to arxiv</title>
    <link>https://www.silviasellan.com/arxiv_compressing.html</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://www.silviasellan.com/arxiv_compressing.html</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I keep forgetting how to do this well, and most of the tricks I find if I just google don&rsquo;t work for me. So, future Silvia, here&rsquo;s what you do:
 Run pip install arxiv-latex-cleaner Run arxiv_latex_cleaner --compress_pdf path/to/tex/folder Compress the new folder path/to/tex/folder-ArXiv and upload that to ArXiv  ]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Running a weekly virtual colloquium</title>
    <link>https://www.silviasellan.com/colloquium.html</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://www.silviasellan.com/colloquium.html</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[A guide to running a weekly virtual colloquium]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>PSA: Update your compositing nodes for 3.0</title>
    <link>https://www.silviasellan.com/blender_compositing_compatibility.html</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://www.silviasellan.com/blender_compositing_compatibility.html</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[For the most part, you can open and render your Blender 2.9 files using the new and improved Blender 3.0. You may want to do this because Blender 3.0&rsquo;s rendering is extremely improved from the previous versions or because you started a project on 2.9/2.8 and now want to continue it in 3.0. There is only one compatibility issue I have encountered, but it can completely destroy your render.
Say your Blender 2.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Bugs I often write in C&#43;&#43;</title>
    <link>https://www.silviasellan.com/cpp_bugs.html</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://www.silviasellan.com/cpp_bugs.html</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Every time I try to code a project in C++ I run into the same bugs, and I keep forgetting how to solve them. So, I decided to write this list here for my own reference.
Eigen initialization bug Symptoms: The code compiles and runs properly, but the output seems random and changes from one run to the next, despite the code being theoretically deterministic.
Diagnosis: This happens because you am declaring a variable and calling it without initializing it.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Rendering a paper figure with Blender</title>
    <link>https://www.silviasellan.com/blender_figure.html</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://www.silviasellan.com/blender_figure.html</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[There are a lot of great Blender tutorials online (e.g., the classic donut tutorial by Blender Guru), and they are usually aimed at artists or animators who want to generate full scenes from scratch for short films. Therefore they go into depth on how to model a shape, how to pick the best lighting, how to design a material, create textures, etc.
These are really interesting topics, but they can be overwhelming if you are an academic and all you want is to render your object beautifully for a SIGGRAPH paper figure.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Preparing PhD Committee Meetings</title>
    <link>https://www.silviasellan.com/phd_committee.html</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://www.silviasellan.com/phd_committee.html</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In my experience, PhD Committee Meetings are an obscure, secretive part of the PhD requirements. One reason for this is that they vary greatly from student to student and discipline to discipline. Still, it is undeniably yet another way in which people without family/friends in academia are gatekept away from it.
When it is your time to prepare a PhD Qualifying Exam or PhD Yearly Checkpoint, it is likely you have never even seen what one looks like before, since they are private events, and have to rely on asking around for examples of successful ones.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>National Day for Truth and Reconciliation</title>
    <link>https://www.silviasellan.com/truth_and_reconciliation.html</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://www.silviasellan.com/truth_and_reconciliation.html</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Today, September 30th 2021, marks the first National Day for Truth and Reconciliation.
A few months ago, I was awarded an NSERC Vanier Graduate Scholarship. I felt incredibly honoured that, less than two years after arriving in this country, the Canadian government was making a choice to bet on my research and spend hard-earned Canadian taxpayer’s money on me.
It came at a strange time, though, as we were getting daily reminders of the historical and present systemic neglect, erasure and discrimination faced by Indigenous people in Canada.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>My application for the Vanier Canada Graduate Scholarship</title>
    <link>https://www.silviasellan.com/vanier_scholarship.html</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://www.silviasellan.com/vanier_scholarship.html</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In 2021, I won a Vanier Canada Graduate Scholarship. Out of 190 total eligible NSERC applicants, I was ranked 43, with scores of 6.50 in Academic Excellence, 6.25 in Research Potential and 7.00 in Leadership (I don&rsquo;t really know a lot about what these numbers mean). NSERC gave out of 55 scholarships, so I got one.
In the last five days alone, I have gotten four emails asking for advice about applying, so out of desire to (1) avoid redundancy and (2) not help only those who dare or are encouraged enough to email me, I am posting my answer here.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
